A Guide to the American Conservation Association (ACA) records FA475
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Whyte, William H., Cluster Development, 1944, 1953-1972, 1974-1976, 1979-1984; 3; 11.24 Cubic Feet Document boxes (part of) 180-208, 1 legal document box, 2 oversized flat boxes
  - Citizens Committee for the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission Report (CORC), Study of Resort Industry, 1962-1963 (Box 192, Folder 1916)
  - Citizens Committee for the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission Report (CORC), Tax Exemptions (Sales and Income and Franchise), 1963-1964 (Box 192, Folder 1917)
  - Citizens Committee for the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission Report (CORC), Virginia, 1964-1965 (Box 192, Folder 1918)
  - Citizens Committee for the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission Report (CORC), William H. Whyte, 1963 (Box 192, Folder 1919)
  - Citizens Committee for the Outdoor Recreation Resources Review Commission Report (CORC), Work Material, 1963-1965 (Box 192, Folder 1920)
  - The Conservation Foundation, 1966-1967 (Box 192, Folder 1921-1922)
  - The Conservation Foundation, Ford Proposal, 1966-1967 (Box 193, Folder 1923)
  - "The Last Landscape", Manuscript Revision, 1967-1968 (Box 193, Folder 1924-1926)
  - Long Island on Natural Beauty, 1965 October 20 (Box 193, Folder 1926)
  - Michigan Conference, 1965 October 12 (Box 193, Folder 1927)
  - Open Space Action Committee, 1965-1967 (Box 193, Folder 1929)
  - Regional Plan Association, 1966 November 10 (Box 194, Folder 1931)
  - Sierra Club Critique, 1962 (Box 194, Folder 1932)
  - Task Force Arrangements Report, 1964 (Box 194, Folder 1933)
  - Virginia Conference, 1965 December 9 (Box 194, Folder 1934)
  - YMCA Conference, 1966 July 17-23 (Box 194, Folder 1935)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission (HRVC), 1965-1968 (Box 194, Folder 1936-1937)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission, (HRVC), Act, 1966 (Box 194, Folder 1938)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission (HRVC), Beautification Grant, 1966-1967 (Box 194, Folder 1939)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission (HRVC), Compact Matters, 1966-1967 (Box 194, Folder 1940)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission (HRVC), Con Edison, 1966 (Box 194, Folder 1941)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission (HRVC), Georgia Pacific Plan, 1966-1967 (Box 194, Folder 1943)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission (HRVC), Goals Memoranda, 1966 (Box 194, Folder 1944)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission (HRVC), Land Acquisition Proposal, 1964, 1966-1967 (Box 195, Folder 1945)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission (HRVC), Minutes, 1965, 1967-1968 (Box 195, Folder 1946-1947)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission (HRVC), Newsletters, 1966-1967 (Box 195, Folder 1948)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission (HRVC), Planning Committee, 1966-1967 (Box 195, Folder 1949)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission (HRVC), Project Review, 1967 (Box 195, Folder 1950)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission (HRVC), Report, Reactions, 1966 (Box 195, Folder 1951)
  - California, American River Parkway, 1961-1962, 1964 (Box 195, Folder 1952)
  - California, Bond Issue, 1962 (Box 195, Folder 1953)
  - California, 1963 Bond Issue, 1961-1964 (Box 195, Folder 1954)
  - California, Department of Natural Resources, 1960 (Box 195, Folder 1955)
  - California, Legislature, Fred Farr and William Lipman, 1959-1963 (Box 196, Folder 1956)
  - California, Loomis Valley, 1958 (Box 196, Folder 1957)
  - California, Los Angeles County, 1961 (Box 196, Folder 1958)
  - California, Monterey County, Carmel Valley, 1959 (Box 196, Folder 1960)
  - California, Monterey County, Clippings, 1961 (Box 196, Folder 1961)
  - California, Monterey County, Scenic Reserve, 1961-1962 (Box 196, Folder 1962)
  - California, Palo Alto, 1960-1961 (Box 196, Folder 1963)
  - California, San Diego, 1960 (Box 196, Folder 1964)
  - California, San Mateo County, 1953-1954, 1958-1959 (Box 196, Folder 1965)
  - California, San Mateo County, Golf Club Situation, 1958-1959, 1961 (Box 196, Folder 1966)
  - California, Santa Barbara, 1959-1961, 1964 (Box 196, Folder 1967)
  - California, Santa Clara County, 1957-1961 (Box 197, Folder 1968)
  - California, Sutter County, Agricultural Zoning, 1962 (Box 197, Folder 1969)
  - California, University of California Site Study, 1958 (Box 197, Folder 1970)
  - California, Samuel Wood, 1962, 1964 (Box 197, Folder 1971)
  - Connecticut, A Proposal for Action, 1962 (Box 197, Folder 1973)
  - Florida, 1963 (Box 197, Folder 1974)
  - Illinois, 1961-1962 (Box 197, Folder 1975)
  - Illinois, Open Space Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 197, Folder 1976)
  - Illinois, Winnebago County, Flood Plain Zoning, 1959-1961 (Box 197, Folder 1977)
  - Indiana, Marion Connty, Metropolitan Department, 1959 (Box 197, Folder 1978)
  - Iowa, Iowa Conservation Boards, 1958, 1960-1961, 1964 (Box 197, Folder 1979)
  - Maryland, Baltimore County, 1961-1962 (Box 197, Folder 1980)
  - Michigan, 1961 (Box 197, Folder 1981)
  - Minnesota (Box 197, Folder 1982)
  - Minnesota, St. Paul, 1961, 1963 (Box 197, Folder 1983)
  - Minnesota, Northfield, 1961 (Box 197, Folder 1984)
  - Missouri, University of Missouri Prairie Preserve, 1959 (Box 197, Folder 1985)
  - New Mexico, Bolack (Box 197, Folder 1986)
  - New York, Highway Legislation, 1966-1967 (Box 197, Folder 1987)
  - Ohio, Dayton, 1961-1963 (Box 197, Folder 1988)
  - Ohio, Glen Helen, 1953, 1959-1960, 1962-1964 (Box 197, Folder 1989)
  - Ohio, Indian Hill, 1962 (Box 197, Folder 1990)
  - Ohio, Ohio Turnpike Commission, 1961 (Box 198, Folder 1991)
  - Puerto Rico, 1960-1963 (Box 198, Folder 1992)
  - Puerto Rico, San Juan, 1961-1963 (Box 198, Folder 1993)
  - Texas, 1962 (Box 198, Folder 1994)
  - Wisconsin, Campaign for Resource Program, 1960-1961 (Box 198, Folder 1995)
  - Wisconsin, Highway Interchange Legislation, 1961 (Box 198, Folder 1996)
  - Wisconsin, Gaylord Nelson, 1961-1962 (Box 198, Folder 1997)
  - Wisconsin, The Program, 1962, 1961-1963 (Box 198, Folder 1999)
  - Town Houses, City, Capitol Park, Washington, D. C., 1963-1964 (Box 198, Folder 2000)
  - Town Houses, City, Colonial Park, Louisville, Kentucky, 1955-1956, 1960-1964 (Box 198, Folder 2001)
  - Town Houses, City, Cross Keys, Baltimore, Maryland, 1962-1963 (Box 198, Folder 2002)
  - Town Houses, City, Dudley Square, Shreveport, Louisiana, 1958-1959, 1962-1963 (Box 198, Folder 2003)
  - Town Houses, City, East Hills, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 1961-1963 (Box 198, Folder 2004)
  - Town Houses, City, Fairway Gardens, New Haven, Connecticut, 1963 (Box 198, Folder 2005)
  - Town Houses, City, Geneva Terrace, San Francisco, 1963 (Box 198, Folder 2006)
  - Town Houses, City, Hartshorn, Richmond, Virginia, 1961, 1963 (Box 199, Folder 2007)
  - Town Houses, City, Huntington Continental, Huntington Beach, California, 1963 (Box 199, Folder 2008)
  - Town Houses, City, Liberty Square, New Haven, Connecticut, 1963 (Box 199, Folder 2009)
  - Town Houses, City, Morrell Park, Far Northeast, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1958, 1961-1963 (Box 199, Folder 2010)
  - Town Houses, City, Park Towne, St. Louis, Missouri, 1963 (Box 199, Folder 2011)
  - Town Houses, City, River Park, Washington, D. C., 1963-1964 (Box 199, Folder 2012)
  - Town Houses, City, Quinnipiac Gardens, New Haven, Connecticut, 1961 June 23 (Folder 2311)
  - Town Houses, City, University Mews, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1964 (Box 199, Folder 2013)
  - Town Houses, City, Vista Bahia, Newport Beach, California, 1962-1963 (Box 199, Folder 2014)
  - Town Houses, City, West Lane Keys and Dumbarton Rock Court, Georgetown, Washington, D. C. (Box 199, Folder 2015)
  - Town Houses, Suburban, Creekside North, Walnut Creek, California, 1963 (Box 199, Folder 2016)
  - Town Houses, Suburban, Georgetown South, Manassas, Virginia, 1963 (Box 199, Folder 2017)
  - Town Houses, Suburban, Heather Hills, Louisville, Kentucky, 1963 (Box 199, Folder 2018)
  - Town Houses, Suburban, Pomeroy Green, Santa Clara, California, 1963 (Box 199, Folder 2019)
  - Town Houses, Suburban, Terrace at Peacock Gap, Marin Bay, California, 1963 (Box 199, Folder 2020)
  - Detached House Clusters, Brunswick Acres, South Brunswick, New Jersey, 1963 (Box 199, Folder 2021)
  - Detached House Clusters, Georgetown East, Cedarburg, Wisconsin, 1963 (Box 199, Folder 2022)
  - Detached House Clusters, Hampden Heights, Denver, Colorado, 1963 (Box 199, Folder 2023)
  - Detached House Clusters, The Highlands, Ledyard, Connecticut, 1963-1964 (Box 199, Folder 2024)
  - Detached House Clusters, Lakeside Hills, St. Louis, Missouri, 1963 (Box 199, Folder 2025)
  - Detached House Clusters, Parkwood, Lowes Grove, North Carolina, 1963 (Box 199, Folder 2026)
  - Detached House Clusters, Sunrise, Guilford, Connecticut, 19963 (Box 200, Folder 2027)
  - Detached House Clusters, Village Green, Hillsborough, New Jeresey, 1961-1963 (Box 200, Folder 2028)
  - Detached House Clusters, Ville du Parc, Mequon, Wisconsin, 1961, 1963 (Box 200, Folder 2029)
  - Detached House Clusters, The Woodlands, Farmington, Connecticut, 1963 (Box 200, Folder 2030)
  - Super Developments, Americana Fairfax, Fairfax County, Virginia, 1963 (Box 200, Folder 2031)
  - Super Developments, Carmel Valley Golf and Country Club, Carmel, California, 1963 (Box 200, Folder 2032)
  - Super Developments, Chapel Hill, Atlanta, Georgia, 1963 (Box 200, Folder 2033)
  - Super Developments, Crofton, Baltimore, Maryland, 1963 (Box 200, Folder 2035)
  - Super Developments, El Dorado Hills, Sacramento, California, 1962-1963 (Box 220, Folder 2298)
  - Super Developments, Four Seasons, St. Louis, Missouri, 1961, 1963 (Box 200, Folder 2036)
  - Super Developments, Greenhaven '70, Sacramento, California, 1962-1963 (Box 200, Folder 2037)
  - Super Developments, Hunting Creek, Louisville, Kentucky, 1963-1964 (Box 200, Folder 2038)
  - Super Developments, Lakehurst, Columbine Community, Denver, Colorado, 1958, 1963 (Box 200, Folder 2039)
  - Super Developments, Loma Vista, Kansas City, Missouri, 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2040)
  - Super Developments, New Seabury, Cape Cod, Massachusetts, 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2041)
  - Super Developments, Reston, Fairfax County, Virginia, 1963-1964 (Box 219, Folder 2291)
  - Super Developments, Sea Pines Plantation, Hilton Head, South Carolina, 1963-1964 (Box 201, Folder 2042)
  - Super Developments, Skyline Forest, Monterey, California, 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2043)
  - Super Developments, Westchester, Springfield, Illinois, 1963-1964 (Box 201, Folder 2044)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Apple Hill, St. Louis, Missouri, 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2045)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Arbor Park and Oxmoor, Louisville, Kentucky, A Prelinimary Study for the Development of Oxmoor Farm, 1963 March 7 (Folder 2311)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Baldwin Hills, Los Angeles, California (Box 201, Folder 2047)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Cincinnati, Ohio, Hamilton County Storm Drainage Plan, 1958, 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2048)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, College Green, Fullerton, California (Box 201, Folder 2049)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Conantum, Concord, Massachusetts and Other Carl Koch Projects, 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2050)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Crystal Shores, Lake Tahoe, Nevada, 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2051)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Fremont, California, 1962 (Box 201, Folder 2052)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Green Manor, Manchester, Connecticut, 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2053)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Guilford Terraces, Connecticut, 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2054)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Hanover East and Peachtree Estates, Atlanta, Georgia, 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2055)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Indian Lake, Somerset, and Indian Creek, Merion, Pennsylvania, 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2056)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Irvine Ranch, Pereira, California, 19963 (Box 201, Folder 2057)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Kansas City. Missouri, Miscellaneous Good Plans by Hare and Hare, All Defeated, 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2058)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Monterey Penninsula, California, 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2059)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Mosby Woods, Virginia (and other Washington, D.C., Maryland and Virginia), 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2060)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, New Castle, Deleware, 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2061)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, North Lake Plan, Wisconsin (Box 201, Folder 2062)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Parkside Estates, Fresno, California, 1963 (Box 201, Folder 2063)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Parkwood, San Jose, California, 1963 (Box 202, Folder 2064)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, St. Louis, Missouri, Community Unit Development, 1963 (Box 202, Folder 2065)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, St. Louis, Missouri, Pierremont and Bellerive Estates, 1963 (Box 219, Folder 2292)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, St. Mary's Close, Shincliffe, England, 1962-1964 (Box 202, Folder 2066)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Society Hill, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1963 (Box 202, Folder 2067)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Starwood, Aspen, Colorado (Box 202, Folder 2068)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Sunnyside Gardens and Radburn, Queens, New York, 1963 (Box 202, Folder 2069)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Washington Heights, Florida, 1963 (Box 202, Folder 2070)
  - Miscellaneous Developments, Williamsburg Square, Phoenix, Arizona, 1964 (Box 202, Folder 2071)
  - Biographical with Developments, Karl Belser, Santa Clara County, California, 1963 (Box 202, Folder 2072)
  - Biographical with Developments, Norman Blankman, Old Westbury, New York and Tenafly, New Jersey, 1962-1963 (Box 202, Folder 2073)
  - Biographical with Developments, Robert Caitlin, Rockaway, New Jersey, 1961, 1963 (Box 202, Folder 2074)
  - Biographical with Developments, Grady Clay, 1960, 1962-1964 (Box 202, Folder 2075)
  - Biographical with Developments, Larry Freels, Rheem Terrace, Lawrence Square, Creekside, etc., California (Box 202, Folder 2076)
  - Biographical with Developments, Victor Gruen (Box 202, Folder 2077)
  - Biographical with Developments, Gerald Lloyd, 1961-1963 (Box 202, Folder 2078)
  - Biographical with Developments, William Nelson, 1963 (Box 202, Folder 2079)
  - Biographical with Developments, John Rahenkamp, Pitney Estates, 1963 (Box 202, Folder 2080)
  - Biographical with Developments, William Roach, Sommerset County, New Jersey, 1963-1964 (Box 202, Folder 2081)
  - Biographical with Developments, Edward Stone House, 1958, 1964 (Box 202, Folder 2082)
  - Biographical with Developments, Lee Syracuse, Connecticut, 1963 (Box 202, Folder 2083)
  - Cluster Study, Subject Files, General Correspondence, 1963 (Box 202, Folder 2084)
  - Cluster Study, Subject Files, Condominium Financing, 1963 (Box 202, Folder 2085)
  - Cluster Study, Subject Files, Density Zoning, Planned Unit Development, 1961-1962 (Box 202, Folder 2086)
  - Cluster Study, Subject Files, FHA (Federal Hosing Administration) Glossary of Terms, 1961-1964 (Box 202, Folder 2087)
  - Cluster Study, Subject Files, Gas Lamps, 1960-1964 (Box 202, Folder 2088)
  - Cluster Study, Subject Files, Home Owners Association Forms, 1963 (Box 203, Folder 2089)
  - Cluster Study, Subject Files, Legal, 1961-1963 (Box 203, Folder 2090)
  - Cluster Study, Subject Files, Miscellaneous Clippings, 1961-1963 (Box 203, Folder 2091)
  - Cluster Study, Subject Files, Propaganda (Box 203, Folder 2092)
  - Cluster Study, Subject Files, Cluster Zoning Ordinances, 1962-1963 (Box 203, Folder 2093)
  - Appendix, Appendix A, Galleys Returned by Developers, 1963 (Box 203, Folder 2094)
  - Appendix, Appendix B and C, Planned Unit Development, 1962-1963 (Box 203, Folder 2095)
  - Appendix, Appendix D, Home Owners Association Index, 1958-1959, 1962-1963 (Box 203, Folder 2096)
  - Appendix, Index (Box 203, Folder 2097)
  - Appendix, Cluster, Critiques, 1963-1964 (Box 203, Folder 2098)
  - Chapters, Forward, 1964 (Box 204, Folder 2099)
  - Chapters, Economics, 1962 (Box 204, Folder 2100)
  - Chapters, The Marketplace (Box 204, Folder 2101)
  - Chapters, The Legal Base, 1963-1964 (Box 204, Folder 2102)
  - Chapters, Homeowners Associations, 1963 (Box 204, Folder 2103)
  - Chapters, Town House, 1963 (Box 204, Folder 2104)
  - Chapters, Super Developments, 1963 (Box 204, Folder 2105)
  - Chapters, Linkage, 1963-1964 (Box 204, Folder 2106)
  - Chapters, Kinds of Spaces, 1961-1963 (Box 204, Folder 2107)
  - Chapters, Captions (Box 204, Folder 2108)
  - The Report, Acknowledgments for Complimentary Copies, 1964 (Box 204, Folder 2109)
  - The Report, Art Work, Nat Streitman, Site Plan Correspondence, 1963 (Box 204, Folder 2110)
  - The Report, Cluster Promotion, Groups, 1963-1964 (Box 204, Folder 2113)
  - The Report, Conservation Foundation Bulletins, 1966-1968 (Box 204, Folder 2114)
  - The Report, Copyright Certificate "Cluster Development", 1964 (Box 204, Folder 2115)
  - The Report, Copyright Forms and Catalogue Number, 1964 (Box 204, Folder 2116)
  - The Report, Cover and Flyer, 1964 (Box 205, Folder 2117)
  - The Report, Distribution (Box 205, Folder 2118)
  - The Report, Distribution, Open Space Return, 1962 (Box 205, Folder 2119)
  - The Report, General File, 1964 (Box 205, Folder 2121)
  - The Report, Inquiries, re: Reprints from Book, 1964 (Box 205, Folder 2123)
  - The Report, Media, Magazines, 1963-1964 (Box 205, Folder 2124)
  - The Report, Media, Newspapers, 1964 (Box 205, Folder 2125)
  - The Report, Media, Television, 1964 (Box 205, Folder 2126)
  - The Report, Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 205, Folder 2128)
  - The Report, Miscellaneous Inquiries Acknowledged, 1964 (Box 205, Folder 2129)
  - The Report, Photographs, Site Plans, 1964 (Box 205, Folder 2130)
  - The Report, Photograph Credit Permissions and Cover, 1963-1964 (Box 205, Folder 2131)
  - The Report, Promotion, Conference, 1964 (Box 205, Folder 2132)
  - The Report, Upcoming Conventions, 1964 (Box 205, Folder 2133)
  - The Report, Urban Sprawl, Newspaper Promotion, 1957-1959 (Box 205, Folder 2134)
  - Hudson River Valley Commission (HRVC), 1967-1968 (Box 219, Folder 2293-2294)
  - Budget and Supplies Ordered, 1963-1964 (Box 205, Folder 2138)
  - Daily Reports of Sales, 1964 (Box 206, Folder 2142)
  - High Meadows, Publications, Oversized, 1961 (Box 220, Folder 2299)
  - Knopf, 1964 (Box 206, Folder 2143)
  - List of Addresses for Distribution (Box 206, Folder 2144)
  - Negatives of All Photographs Used (Box 206, Folder 2150)
  - Photographs, Unlabeled (Box 206, Folder 2154)
  - Printing Negotiations, 1963-1964 (Box 208, Folder 2187)
  - Publication Details, 1964 (Box 208, Folder 2188)
  - Urban America, 1965-1966 (Box 208, Folder 2189)
- Publications, 1961-1965, 1974, 1979, 2000, 2002; 4; .66 Cubic Feet Document box (part of) 208-209. 1 short oversized document box
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., "A More Beautiful America...", 1965 (Box 221, Folder 2309)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., "A More Beautiful America," Mockup (Box 221, Folder 2310)
  - LaFarge, Albert (Edited), The Essential Willaim H. Whyte, 2000 (Box 209, Folder 2194)
  - Richard King Mellon Foundation, American Land Conservsataion Program, 1988-2002, From Sea to Shining Sea (Box 209, Folder 2195)